Pablo Vieytes

Software Engineer
Madrid, Spain
Nationality: Spanish
Email: pablo@onytes.com
Github profile: pvieytes

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Software engineer with seven years experience of developing and testing software. Since 2010 I have specialized in web technologies. I am self starter and quick to assimilate new ideas, concepts and cutting-edge technologies. I have a command of spoken and written English.

OBJECTIVE

I am currently looking for a new and challenging position to work on high availability systems, one which will make the best use of my existing skills and experience and help me develop my career as a web designer and developer.

CERTIFICATIONS

Erlang Certification Erlang Foundation Certificate – January 2013

Certificate number: ESL20130118/01

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

BSc Telecommunications Engineering. Electronic Systems (2007) – Polytechnic

University of Madrid

Thesis: Data Acquisition and Digital Signal Processing with Matlab

KEY TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, Java, Erlang, C/C++, JavaScript

- Web technologies: Django, HTML, CSS, RESTful, Ajax jQuery, websockets...
- Data base: Sql and no-sql (PostgreSQL, Mysql, Neo4j, Riak)
- Others: Linux, Android, Git, eclipse

WORK HISTORY

January 2014 – Present Freelance WEB DEVELOPER

Design, development and deployment of website projects.

• Halfare: Social carpooling platform for commuters.

April 2010 – December 2013

Openshine S.L., Remote (Madrid and Essen) WEB DEVELOPER

Sofware development and computing consultancy.

- Designing and developing Python/Django web applications.
- Designing and developing of a concurrent distributed system based on Erlang/OTP and websockets.

2007–2010 CITEF - Polytechnic University of Madrid R&D ENGINEER

R&D engineering in *Research Centre on Railway Technologies (CITEF)* being part of the Polytechnic University of Madrid (UPM). Designing and developing software for the railway industry.

- Designing and developing of an automatic planning and exploitation management system for railway lines and underground for TELVENT.
- Developing of Matlab programs for data acquisition and signal spectrum analysis.
- Testing and improving software of the THALES GLR-95 circuit track.
- Software modelling of circuit track for DIMETRONIC.
- Electromagnetic disturbances measuring and documentation-producing by high speed lines in the conventional lines prior to the commissioning of the lines for the Spanish railway infrastructure manager ADIF.
- Electromagnetic disturbances measuring and documentation-producing by boarding equipment to THALES-MEXICO.

2003–2007 CITEF - Polytechnic University of Madrid R&D TRAINEE ENGINEER

R&D engineering in *Research Centre on Railway Technologies (CITEF)* being part of the Polytechnic University of Madrid (UPM).

- Designing and developing software and hardware for the railway industry.
- Designing and developing hardware and software for a data acquisition system placed in a train pantograph for *Metro Madrid*.
- Analysing, designing and developing of an Active Noise Canceller prototype.
- Electronic Hardware Design (PCB Design).

INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES

Hobbies & activities

Music, building guitar vacuum tubes amps and playing the guitar and the trumpet.